My name is Anthony Maddaloni, and I'm going to talk about how to become a medical photographer.
Now, a medical photographer is a photographer that documents, essentially, facts for doctors, insurance companies, hospitals, patient rights advocates, and what you're really doing -- it could be anywhere from taking slides of literally accidents, potentially surgeries going on, and documenting them properly.
And it's more of a technical type of photography than action-based photography.
And one way you might want to break into this type of photography is to go to a medical school and see what a medical school...who they use, and assist.
Like any other type of photography that I talk about, really, your first little foot in the door is finding someone who does it professionally and spend a day with them and see what it's like because it might not be anything what you think it's like or it might be even better than you think it is, and you can find out that you're suited for that type of photography.
Now, medical photography is a type of photography where you're probably going to be using something...a digital camera.
You want to make sure that you have a digital camera that can make a nice, a rather large file because you never know what these...
These could be used in a court case, they could be used for lectures, med school.
So you want to make sure you have the right equipment in order to do this type of photography.
You wouldn't use cameras that you would, say, use for photojournalism for medical photography.
You might be using a completely different type of set up.
So that's one way.
The other thing is to look at a lot of different types of medical photography out there.
That could be medical journals, websites, and see, you know, is this something that I think I can be good at?
Can I understand this type of composition?
So those are some of the ways that I would become a medical photographer.